iqstudentaccommodation.com 2018-12-24

# Privacy Centre | iQ Student Accommodation

Welcome to iQ's Privacy Centre. The information contained on this page and through the attached links provides details of how we manage, process and store your personal data.

We take the security of your data extremely seriously and iQ is committed to ensure compliance with all applicable data protection legislation.

iQ Student Accommodation through its group structure is a Data Controller and a Data Processor. iQ will also provide your information with its chosen business partners for the purposes of managing your tenancy. These business partners are data processors acting on behalf of iQ and covered by data processing agreements between us.

You can read more about this and find details of how we acquire, store, process and eventually delete your personal information in our Privacy Notice which can be found by clicking here.

If you want to see our Cookies policy please click here.

If you want to see a list of companies that make up the IQSA Group, please click here

If you want to see our recruitment privacy statement please click here.

**Individuals’ rights and how to exercise them**

Individuals, also referred to as Data Subjects, have certain rights over their personal data and as a Data Controller, iQ is responsible for fulfilling these rights. iQ is a Data Controller because we decide how and why personal data is processed, and include further information about the rights that you have over your data and how to exercise them below.

**Access to personal data**

You have a right of access to personal data held by us as a Data Controller. This is referred to as a Data Subject Access Request. This right may be exercised by downloading our Data Subject Access request form and emailing it to us at [dpo@iqstudent.com](mailto:dpo@iqstudent.com). You can download a form here that will allow us to provide copies of the information you require. You must provide us with proof of your identification without which we will not be able to fulfil your request. There is no charge for providing this information although if you make persistent requests for the same or similar data, the request is excessive or considered vexatious, we are permitted to make a charge based on the administrative costs involved in providing this information.

We will respond to your request within one month of its receipt. If we are unable to respond within this timeframe we will write to you before the expiry of this period and tell you when we expect to be able to provide the copies of the data you have requested.

**Amendment of personal data**

There are several ways to update personal data submitted to us. If you are a resident the best way to do this is to speak to one of our team members at reception during normal opening hours.  If you are not a yet a resident or you have stayed with us before and/or you are aware that we hold personal details about you that you believe are inaccurate, you may email us at [dpo@iqstudent.com](mailto:dpo@iqstudent.com).

If you are a supplier and wish to change your details, please contact our procurement team at [procurement@iqstudent.com](mailto:procurement@iqstudent.com).

When practically possible, once we are informed that any personal data processed by us is no longer accurate, we will make corrections (where appropriate) based on your updated information. We will do this within one month of receiving your request and we will confirm to you that we have complied with your request.

**Withdrawal of consent**

Where we process personal data based on consent, you as a Data Subject have a right to withdraw consent at any time.  We do not generally process personal data for the purposes of managing your application or tenancy based on consent (as we can usually rely on another legal basis to process this information).

To withdraw consent to our processing of your personal data please email us at [dpo@iqstudent.com.](mailto:dpo@iqstudent.com.) or, to stop receiving an email from an iQ marketing list to which you have previously consented, please click on the unsubscribe link in the relevant email received from us.  You can find more details in our Privacy Notice about the basis of processing your personal information by clicking here.

**Other data subject rights**

Our Privacy Notice is intended to provide information about what personal data we collect about you and how it is used.  As well as rights of access and amendment referred to above, individuals may have other rights in relation to the personal data we hold, such as a right to erasure/deletion, to restrict or object to our processing of personal data and the right to data portability.  

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please send an email to [dpo@iqstudent.com](mailto:dpo@iqstudent.com).

**Complaints**

We hope that you won’t ever need to, but if you do want to complain about our use of your personal data, please send an email with the details of your complaint to [dpo@iqstudent.com](mailto:dpo@iqstudent.com).  You may also write to us at the address below. We will look into and respond to any complaints we receive.

Data Protection Officer  
Compliance Department  
iQ Student Accommodation  
7th Floor East,  
Cottons Centre  
Hays Lane  
London SE1 2QG

We will normally acknowledge your complaint within 2 working days and provide a full response within 1 month.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office (“ICO”) (the UK data protection regulator).  For further information on your rights and how to complain to the ICO, please refer to the [ICO website](https://ico.org.uk/).
